Louis Skidmore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Louis Skidmore Papers 1908-1976
MSS75892
Skidmore, Louis, 1897-1962
2,000 items
4 containers plus 1 oversize
1.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Architect. Correspondence, diaries, subject files, family papers, and other papers relating chiefly to Skidmore’s career as an architect.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Emerson, William Ralph, 1833-1917.; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981.; Skidmore family.; Skidmore, Louis, 1897-1962.
Organizations
American Institute of Architects.; Skidmore, Owings & Merrill.
Subjects
Architectural firms.; Architecture--Societies, etc.; Architecture.
Occupations
Architects.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Louis Skidmore, architect, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Eloise Owings Skidmore, in 1978.
Transfers
Architectural drawings, photographs, sketches, oil paintings, and postal cards have been transferred to the Library’s Pints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Louis Skidmore are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1897, Apr. 8 Born, Lawrenceburg, Ind.
1911 1915 Attended Manual Training High School, Peoria, Ill.
1915 1917 Studied at Bradley Polytechnical Institute, Peoria, Ill.
1915 1919 Employed chiefly at Avery Tractor Co., Peoria, Ill.
1918 1919 Served in U.S. Army
1919 1920 Instructor in cabinet and pattern making, Pullman Free School of Manual Training, Chicago, Ill.
1920 Architectural designer with Kruckemeyer and Strong, Cincinnati, Ohio
1921 1923 Studied at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass.
1924 1926 Architectural designer, Maginnis and Walsh, Boston, Mass.
1926 1928 Rotch Traveling Fellowship
1929 1932 Chief of design, Century of Progress International Exposition, Chicago, Ill.
1930 Married Eloise Owings
1935 Opened architectural office of Skidmore & Owings, Chicago, Ill.
1936 1937 Director of the School of Architecture, Armour Institute, Chicago, Ill
1938 Adviser to New York's World Fair, New York, N.Y.
1962, Sept. 27 Died, Winter Haven, Fla.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Louis Skidmore (1897-1962) span the years 1908-1976 and consist of correspondence, diaries, subject files, family papers, and other papers relating chiefly to Skidmore's career as an architect. Included in the collection is material pertaining to William Ralph Emerson, Robert Moses, the American Institute of Architects, and the firm of Skidmore, Owings & Merrill.
Arrangement of the Papers
The papers are organized by type of material.
Container List
- Diaries (Box 1)
  - 1908, Skidmore's grandmother (Box 1)
  - 1918, World War I (Box 1)
  - 1926, Rotch Traveling Fellowship, (2 vols.) (Box 1)
- Workbook, high school, 1913-1914 (Box 1)
- Family correspondence, 1918 (Box 2)
- General correspondence, 1916-1976, undated, (7 folders) (Box 2)
- Letters of condolence, 1962-1963, (5 folders) (Box 2)
- List of friends to be notified (Box 2)
- Subject files (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Architects Gold Medal of Honor, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1949 (Box 3)
    - 1957 (Box 3)
  - Emerson, William, 1957-1962, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Moses, Robert, 1947-1960 (Box 3)
  - Poems, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Boykin (Box 3)
    - Winsor (Box 3)
  - Skidmore, Owings & Merrill, 1949-1962 (Box 3)
  - "Tudor Homes in England," 1928 (Box 3)
- Miscellany (Box 4)
  - Awards and certificates See Oversize (Box 4)
  - Bills and receipts (Box 4)
  - Biographical material (Box 4)
  - Birth certificate copy (Box 4)
  - Business cards, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Century of Progress International Exposition, Chicago, Ill, 1933-1935 (Box 4)
  - Rotch Fellowship travels, 1927-1928 (Box 4)
  - Conquest of heart disease (Box 4)
  - Donations in memory of Skidmore (Box 4)
  - Hotels, 1927-1928 (Box 4)
  - Invitations (Box 4)
  - Memorial tribute (Box 4)
  - Military records, 1918-1919 (Box 4)
  - Passports, 1928-1952 (Box 4)
- Oversize (Box OV 1)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Awards and certificates (Container 4) (Box OV 1)